<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Octavi Font</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Octavi Font</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:57:34 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software consultant specialized in AI for healthcare. My track record includes the implementation of 2 CAD systems for automated screening of lung cancer nodules and retina pathologies.
I love turning open-ended research questions into products. I believe that the key to applied research is following an iterative approach, focusing first on the subproblems that will yield a better understanding of the overall goal. I find systems designed in such a manner to be loosely coupled, easier to scale and have better product focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinkpad X1 Carbon 6th Gen (2018) on Ubuntu 19.04</title>
      <link>/post/thinkpad-x1-carbon-6th-gen-2018-on-ubuntu-19-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:57:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thinkpad-x1-carbon-6th-gen-2018-on-ubuntu-19-04/</guid>
      <description>This is my recipe to install Ubuntu 19.04 Disco Dingo on the Lenovo Thinkpad X1 Carbon 6th gen (2018). This guide should serve you as well for Ubuntu 18.04 LTS, but the newer kernel and GNOME on 19.04 offer better power management and HiDPI support.
The X1 Carbon is an excellent laptop for developers, and even though its Linux support is good, getting it to work perfectly still requires some tinkering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HiDPI support on Ubuntu 19.04</title>
      <link>/post/hidpi-support-on-ubuntu-19-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 22:12:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hidpi-support-on-ubuntu-19-04/</guid>
      <description>This is how I&amp;rsquo;ve setup my Thinkpad X1 Carbon with functional fractional scaling support on Ubuntu 19.04. Hopefully this post serves as a beacon for everyone wanting a way out of the current buggy mess that is fractional scaling on Linux. The only limitation of this solution is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support dual monitors with different DPI settings. External monitors work well, as long as the laptop screen is closed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIABETIC RETINOPATHY</title>
      <link>/project/diabetic_retinopathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:06:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/diabetic_retinopathy/</guid>
      <description>Auto screening of Digital Fundus Imaging Automatic screening of diabetic retinopathy using digital fundus imaging on retina.
Currently working on this. TBD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LUCANODE</title>
      <link>/project/lucanode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:06:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lucanode/</guid>
      <description>Automatic lung cancer nodule detection Abstract Lung cancer is both the deadliest and one of the most frequently diagnosed forms of the disease. The main cause for the low survivability of lung cancer is due to its lack of early symptoms, which are only detected in terminal stages of the disease. It has been demonstrated that performing screenings in high-risk population increased the survivability by 20% but detecting lung lesions in CT imaging is time consuming and highly dependent on the skill of the radiologist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBSHARING</title>
      <link>/project/nbsharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:06:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nbsharing/</guid>
      <description>Share your data science reports Developed a pastebin for jupyter notebooks. Very useful to share reports with your clients and colleagues in a private manner. Just drag &amp;amp; drop your notebook and you will get a link you can share.
It&amp;rsquo;s free to use. Enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBIMIND</title>
      <link>/project/ubimind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:06:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ubimind/</guid>
      <description>EEG powered wheelchair TBD</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>